

# Francesco Zaniol

Senior Frontend Engineer | Frontend Architect Contractor / Freelance • Remote EU <u>fzaniol@gmail.com</u> | <u>Linkedin</u>

## **About**

I am a Frontend Engineer with 15 years of industry experience.

I create fast, user-friendly, secure and accessible websites and apps, while delivering robust and efficient solutions. Throughout my career I have contributed to successful products and campaigns for leading international brands.

I work remotely from Italy on a B2B contract basis, short or long term.

# Top skills

Vue/Nuxt • React/Next • Typescript • Web Accessibility • Design System • Testing • Tailwind • Animations • Agile • Responsive Design • Git • API/GraphQL • Vite/Webpack • UX • Debugging • Performance • SEO • Cross-browser • Web Components • PHP • Laravel • Wordpress • DRY • Teamplayer

# Work experience

### MAIZE | H-FARM Innovation | JAKALA

2018-2023 (5 years 6 months) • Italy (Full remote)

Role: Senior Frontend Engineer | Frontend Architect

Vue/Nuxt, React, TypeScript, Testing, Design Systems, Laravel, Animations, Agile

Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

Bulgari, Loro Piana, SNAM, Henkel, Barilla, Aquafil, other brands under NDA in the fields of: Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Eyewear, Automotive, Telecoms, Clothing, Digital Learning, Aerospace, Defense and Security

## **IE Agency**

2014-2017 (3 years) • Melbourne, Australia

Role: Lead Frontend Developer • movember.com

Team Lead & Mentor, Agile, Design System, Testing, React, PHP, Zend

Client: The Movember Foundation

World's top 100 NGOs • Global Fundraising | 1.8 billion raised | 1.7 million participants

### **AKQA | H-ART**

2012-2013 (1 year 6 months) • Italy

Role: Frontend Developer

Animations, Landing Pages, Wordpress, Drupal

#### Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

FIAT, Telecom Italia, GEOX, Barilla, IKEA, Illy, Bacardi, Fendi, Intesa Sanpaolo, OVS, Alessi, Poste Italiane, Toyota, Whirpool, other brands under NDA in the fields of: Food & Drink Industry, Automotive, Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Telecoms, Clothing, Home Appliances

### accessibletemplate.com

2012-2017 (5 years 2 months) • Worldwide | Online digital store

Role: Founder | Fullstack Engineer

Accessibility, Personal Business, Joomla Templates, PHP

Clients: Private & Government Websites

WCAG, European Accessibility Act, Section 508, Equality Act, Legge Stanca

#### **AWDD Media**

2010 (7 months) • Vancouver, Canada

Role: Frontend Developer

Drupal, PSD to HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, HTML5

Clients: Local Businesses

#### Freelance

2008-2011 (3 years 5 months) • Italy

Role: Web Developer

Joomla Websites

Clients: Local Businesses

## Education

## Ca' Foscari University, Venice

2004 - 2008 (3 years 6 months)

Degree, Information Technology

Grade: 107/110

#### ITIS Max Plank

1999 - 2004 (5 years)

High school diploma, Information Technology

Grade: 100/100